Nasir Watts



nasirwatts@outlook.com



linkedin.com/in/nasir-watts10100



5138048897



https://www.thetechconsultant.dev

Summary

Hello World! I'm Nasir, a skilled professional with over 8 years of shared experience in Salesforce development and prior expertise in Java, REACT, and CRM integrations. I'm not just a developer but a problem solver, constantly pushing the boundaries to increase analytics and revenue. I've worked with diverse industries such as advertising agencies, dining, furniture and decor brands, finance, and banking. My programming knowledge, cloud development skills, and platform experience have allowed me to make a significant impact in delivering tailored experiences at scale.

Experience



WF Senior Consultant Technical Lead

Wells Fargo

Jun 2022 - Jun 2023 (1 year 1 month)

- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams and marketers to deliver projects on tight deadlines.
- Led the integration into the Salesforce Platform using REST and SOAP operations.
- Expertly utilized Lightning Experience and its components to enhance the user interface and improve the user experience.
- Leveraged Apex for server-side operations, creating robust, scalable, and secure solutions.
- Implemented custom Lightning Web Components (LWC), Flows, Apex, and Aura components to optimize business processes, leading to a 5% increase in workflow production accuracy.
- Built strong relationships with teammates, partners, and stakeholders, fostering a productive working environment.
- Worked cross-platform with marketing cloud tools such as AMPscript, SSJS, GTL, HTML, and Journey Building, contributing to the successful execution of marketing campaigns.



Salesforce Developer

Charles Schwab

Jan 2022 - Jun 2022 (6 months)

- Facilitated the migration from Selligent to Salesforce Marketing Cloud, ensuring a seamless transition.
- Demonstrated proficiency in Apex programming and Salesforce declarative development by developing and implementing custom APIs and web services to integrate data.
- Managed the Salesforce platform using Apex for custom functionality and declarative tools for workflow automation, security settings, and data modeling.
- Developed and maintained integration code, scripts, and configurations supporting data flow and synchronization.
- Used declarative functionality, such as Process Builder and Flow Builder, to invoke Apex code and create flows to handle complex business logic.
- Introduced innovative solutions for handling complex dynamic scripting in banking account information, improving efficiency using SOQL, SOSL, and advanced Apex.
- Continually improved workflows and data validation guidelines to increase organizational-wide business process effectiveness.

Marketing Cloud Developer

Barkley

Mar 2021 - Jan 2022 (11 months)

- Crafted real-time emails using JSON, GTL, AMPscript, SSJS, Send-Definition, and Payload development.
- Developed Send Definitions and Payload for API sends in triggered and transactional emails.
- Surpassed project efficiency goals by 15% through effective time management.
- · Contributed to the company's year-over-year revenue growth by delivering high-quality work.
- Automated the reporting process for IHOP and Applebee's coupon codes, resulting in securing a new contract.

Campaign Engineer

American Century Investments

Jan 2021 - Mar 2021 (3 months)

- Work with B to B and B to C business units.
- Develop, deploy, and test all campaigns across Salesforce Marketing Cloud, Salesforce Lightning, and Pardot.
- Implementation of customer surveys, integrating with cloud pages.
- Responsible for building one-time send automation and customer journeys.

gr Email Marketing Technologist

Grandin Road

Apr 2018 - Jan 2021 (2 years 10 months)

- Transitioned from the team at Frontgate to the team at Grandin Road to lead the Journey implementation for custom customer segmentation and A/B testing.
- · Manage team projects using Basecamp.
- Used Adobe Photoshop to optimize images for the web.
- Use Google Analytics to review and improve all current marketing processes based on actionable data.
- Develop, deploy, and test all promotional, transactional, and triggered emails.

FG Email Developer

FRONTGATE

Mar 2017 - Apr 2018 (1 year 2 months)

- Worked with multiple business units under the Cornerstone brand.
- · Manage team projects using Basecamp.
- Used Adobe Photoshop to optimize images for the web.
- Use Google Analytics to review and improve all current marketing processes based on actionable data.
- Develop, deploy, and test all promotional, transactional, and triggered emails.

React Developer

SS&C Primatics

May 2015 - Feb 2017 (1 year 10 months)

• Responsible for contributing to the design and development of user interfaces.

- · Identify UX pain points and provide knowledgeable recommendations for implementing a unified user experience.
- · Operate in an Agile-governed workplace to best use team resources while achieving project
- · Work with UI/UX designers and product managers to help design and build application user interactions.

Education



Wright State University

Computer Science 2008 - 2015

Licenses & Certifications

- Salesforce Certified Marketing Cloud Email Specialist Salesforce 22752639
- Salesforce Certified Marketing Cloud Developer Salesforce 22903657
- Salesforce Certified Javascript Developer Salesforce 3418135
- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I Salesforce 3461393
- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer II Salesforce 3487648

Skills

AJAX • Jest • Data Integration • Salesforce Lightning • Vanilla JavaScript • Aura • Visualforce Pages • Pub/Sub API • Apex Programming • Declarative Programming